in the United States
في الولايات المتحدة
than any other organization.
أكثر من أي منظمة أخرى
More than al Qaeda,
أكثر من القاعدة
more than al Shabaab,
أكثر من الشباب
more than the Islamic State,
أكثر من الدولة الإسلامية
more than all of them combined.
أكثر منها كلها مجتمعة
This isn't likely how you think about the FBI.
لم تكن تظن أن مكتب التحقيقات الفدرالي FBI (م ت ف) هكذا
You probably think of FBI agents gunning down bad guys like John Dillinger,
ربما ظننت أن عملاء مكتب التحقيقات الفدرالي يطلقون الرصاص على الأشرار مثل جون دلينجر
or arresting corrupt politicians.
والقبض على السياسيين الفاسدين
After the 9/11 terrorist attacks,
بعد الهجمات الإرهابية 11 سبتمبر
the FBI became less concerned
"م ت ف" أصبح أقل اهتماما
with gangsters and crooked elected officials.
برجال العصابات والمسؤولين المنتخبين المعوجين
The new target became terrorists,
الهدف الجديد صار الإرهابيين
and the pursuit of terrorists has consumed the FBI.
وملاحقة الإرهابيين قد أنهك مكتب التحقيقات الفدرالي.
Every year, the Bureau spends 3.3 billion dollars
ينفق المكتب كل سنة 3,3 مليار دولار
on domestic counterterrorism activities.
على أنشطة مكافحة الإرهاب المحلي
Compare than to just 2.6 billion dollars combined for organized crime,
مقارنة مع فقط 2.6 مليار دولار شاملة الجريمة المنظمة
financial fraud, public corruption
الاحتيال المالي، الفساد العام
and all other types of traditional criminal activity.
وكل الأنواع الأخرى من اللأنشطة الإجرامية الاعتيادية
I've spent years pouring through the case files
قضيت سنوات أدقق في ملفات القضية
of terrorism prosecutions in the United States,
من الملاحقات القضائية للإرهاب داخل الولايات المتحدة
and I've come to the conclusion that the FBI
وخلصت باستنتاج مفاده أن "م ت ف "
is much better at creating terrorists than it is at catching terrorists.
أكثر براعة في صنع الإرهابيين مما هو عليه في القبض على الإرهابيين
In the 14 years since 9/11,
خلال الأربعة عشر سنة منذ 11 سبتمبر
you can count about six real terrorist attacks in the United States.
يمكنك أن تعدّ حوالي ست هجمات إرهابية في الولايات المتحدة
These include the Boston Marathon bombings in 2013,
بما فيها انفجار ماراثون بوسطن في 2013
as well as failed attacks,
وكذلك الهجمات الفاشلة
such as the time when a man named Faisal Shahzad
كتلك اللحظة التي حاول فيها رجل يدعى فيصل شاهزاد
tried to deliver a car bomb to Times Square.
إدخال سيارة مفخخة إلى ساحة تايمز سكوير
In those same 14 years,
في نفس تلك 14 عاما
the Bureau, however, has bragged
المكتب، ومع ذلك، قد تفاخر
about how it's foiled dozens of terrorism plots.
بكيف أحبط عشرات المؤامرات الإرهابية
In all, the FBI has arrested more than 175 people
في المجمل اعتقل مكتب التحقيقات الفدرالي أكثر من 175 شخصا
in aggressive, undercover conterterrorism stings.
بعدوانية، و ضربات استباقية سرية لمواجهة الإرهاب
These operations, which are usually led by an informant,
هذه العمليات التي غالبا ما يقودها مخبر
provide the means and opportunity,
يوفر الوسائل والفرص
and sometimes even the idea,
وأحيانا حتى هذه الفكرة
for mentally ill and economically desperate people
لمختل عقليا و اليائسين اقتصاديا
to become what we now term terrorists.
ليصبحوا ما نطلق عليه الآن مصطلح الإرهابيين
After 9/11, the FBI was given an edict:
بعد 11 سبتمبر. أعطي "م ت ف " مرسوما
never again.
ليس مرة أخرى
Never another attack on American soil.
لا هجمات أخرى على الأراضي الأمريكية
FBI agents were told to find terrorists before they struck.
قيل لعملاء "م ت ف" أن يجدوا الإرهابيين قبل أن يضربوا
To do this, agents recruited a network of more than 15,000 informants nationwide,
للقيام بهذا، جند العملاء شبكة من أكثر من 15000 مخبر على الصعيد الوطني
all looking for anyone who might be dangerous.
يبحثون جميعا عن أي شخص قد يكون خطيراً
An informant can earn 100,000 dollars or more
يمكن أن يجني مخبر 100,000 دولار أو أكثر
for every terrorism case they bring to the FBI.
لكل حالة إرهاب يبلغ عنها ل"م ت ف"
That's right, the FBI is paying mostly criminals and con men
هذا صحيح، "م ت ف" يدفع لأشخاص معظمهم من المجرمين والمخادعين
six figures to spy on communities in the United States,
ستة أرقام للتجسس على المجتمعات في الولايات المتحدة،
but mostly Muslim American communities.
لكن أغلبها المجتمعات الأميركية المسلمة
These informants nab people like Abu Khalid Abdul-Latif
هؤلاء المخبرين يعتقلون الناس مثل أبو خالد عبد اللطيف
and Walli Mujahidh.
و والي مجاهد
Both are mentally ill.
كلاهما مختل عقليا
Abdul-Latif had a history of huffing gasoline and attempting suicide.
وعبد اللطيف له تاريخ من التخدير بشم البنزين ومحاولة الانتحار.
Mujahidh had schizoaffective disorder,
ومجاهد كان يعاني من اضطراب فصامي عاطفي
he had trouble distinguishing between reality and fantasy.
وقد واجه صعوبة في التمييز بين الواقع والخيال
In 2012, the FBI arrested these two men
في 2012، أوقف "م ت ف " أوقفت هذين الرجلين
for conspiring to attack a military recruiting station outside Seattle
بتهمة التآمر لمهاجمة محطة للتجنيد العسكري خارج سياتل
with weapons provided, of course, by the FBI.
بواسطة أسلحة قدمها "م ت ف " طبعا
The FBI's informant was Robert Childs,
مخبر "م ت ف" كان هو روبرت تشايلدز
a convicted rapist and child molester
مدان بالاغتصاب والاستغلال الجنسي للأطفال
who was paid 90,000 dollars for his work on the case.
الذي حصل على 90،000 دولار لعمله على هذه القضية
This isn't an outlier.
هذه ليست نشازا
In 2009, an FBI informant who had fled Pakistan on murder charges
في سنة 2009، مخبر "م ت ف" فارّ من باكستان بتهمة القتل
led four men in a plot to bomb synagogues in the Bronx.
قاد أربعة رجال في مؤامرة لتفجير المعابد اليهودية في برونكس
The lead defendant was James Cromitie,
وكان المتهم الرئيسي جيمس كروميتي
a broke Walmart employee with a history of mental problems.
موظف مطرود من "وول مارت" لديه تاريخ من المشاكل العقلية
And the informant had offered him 250,000 dollars
وقد أعطاه المخبر 250,000 دولار
if he participated in that plot.
إذا شارك في تلك المؤامرة
There are many more examples.
هناك المزيد من الأمثلة
Today, The Intercept published my new story
اليوم، نشرت " ذا انترسبت" قصتي الجديدة
about a counterterrorism sting in Tampa involving Sami Osmakac,
عن مكافحة الإرهاب في "تامبا" بما في ذلك سامي أوسماكاش
a young man who was living near Tampa, Florida.
شاب كان يعيش قرب تامبا، فلوريدا
Osmakac also had schizoaffective disorder.
أوسْماكاش كان يعاني من اضطراب فصامي عاطفي
He too was broke,
وقد كان مطروداً أيضا
and he had no connections to international terrorist groups.
ولم تكن له صلة بالجماعات الإرهابية الدولية
Nonetheless,
ومع ذلك
an FBI informant gave him a job, handed him money,
وقدم له مخبر مكتب التحقيقات الفيدرالي وظيفة، وسلمه المال
introduced him to an undercover agent posing as a terrorist,
قدم له عميل سري تظاهر بأنه إرهابي
and lured him in a plot to bomb an Irish bar.
وجذبه إليه في مؤامرة لتفجير حانة ايرلندية
But here's what's interesting:
ولكن هنا ما هو مثير للاهتمام
The lead undercover agent --
العميل السري الرئيسي
you can see him in this picture with his face blurred --
يمكنكم رؤيته في هذه الصورة مع وجه مضبب
would go back to the Tampa field office with his recording equipment on.
عاد إلى المكتب الميداني تامبا بمعدات تسجيل له
Behind closed doors,
خلف الأبواب المغلقة،
FBI agents admitted that what they were doing was farcical.
اعترف عملاء مكتب التحقيقات الفيدرالي أن ما كانوا يفعلون كان مهزلة
A federal judge doesn't want you to hear about these conversations.
قاض اتحادي لا يريد لكم أن تسمعوا عن هذه المحادثات
He sealed the transcripts and placed them under a protective order
ختم النصوص ووضعها بموجب أمر وقائي
in an attempt to prevent someone like me from doing something like this.
في محاولة لمنع أي شخص مثلي من فعل شيئ كهذا
the squad supervisor,
مشرف الفريق
described their would-be terrorist
وصف الشخص الذي سيكون "الإرهابي "
as a "retarded fool who didn't have a pot to piss in."
بأنه " متخلف عقليا و أحمق"
They described his terrorist ambitions
لقد وصفوا طموحاته الإرهابية
as wishy-washy and a pipe dream scenario.
بأنه ضعيف الشخصية و يعيش سيناريو من الأوهام
But that didn't stop the FBI.
ولكن هذا لم يمنع "م ت ف"
They provided Sami Osmakac everything he needed.
من تزويد سامي أوسماكاش بكل شيء احتاجه
They gave him a car bomb, they gave him an AK-47,
أعطوه سيارة مفخخة أعطوه رشاش كلاشنكوف
they helped him make a so-called martyrdom video,
ساعدوه على صنع على ما يسمى فيديو استشهادي
and they even gave him money for a taxi cab
وحتى المال لسيارة الأجرة قدموه له
so that he could get to where they wanted him to go.
حتى أنه يمكن أن نصل إلى حيث أرادوا منه أن يذهب
As they were working the sting,
مثل ما كانوا يعملون للضربة
the squad supervisor tells his agents he wanted a Hollywood ending.
مشرف الفرقة يخبر عملاءه أنه يريد نهاية هوليودية
And he got a Hollywood ending.
وقد حصل على نهاية هوليودية
When Sami Osmakac attempted to deliver what he thought
عندما حاول سامي أوسماكاش تسليم ما اعتقد أنها
was a car bomb,
كانت سيارة مفخخة
he was arrested, convicted and sentenced to 40 years in prison.
اعتقل وأدين و حكم عليه بالسجن 40 عاما
Sami Osmakac isn't alone.
سامي أوسماكاش ليس وحيدا
He's one of more than 175 so-called terrorists,
إنه واحد من أكثر من 175 يسمون إرهابيين
for whom the FBI has created Hollywood endings.
ممن صنع لهم "م ت ف" نهايات هوليودية
U.S. government officials call this the War on Terror.
حكومة الولايات المتحدة تسميها حربا على الإرهاب
It's really just theater,
إنها حقا مجرد مسرحية
a national security theater,
مسرحية الأمن القومي
with mentally ill men like Sami Osmakac
بمرضى عقليين مثل سامي أوسماكاش
unwitting actors in a carefully choreographed production
وممثلين عن غير قصد في انتاجات محبوكة بعناية
brought to you by the FBI.
قدمت لكم من طرف "م ت ف"
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Tom Rielly: So, those are some pretty strong accusations,
توم رايلي: إذن، تلك اتهامات قوية جدا،
pretty strong charges.
إدانة قوية جدا
How can you back this up?
كيف يمكنك أن تدعم هذه الفرضية؟
Trevor Aaronson: My research began in 2010
تريفور أرونسون: بدأت أبحاثي في ​​سنة 2010
when I received a grant from the Investigative Reporting Program
عندما حصلت على موافقة من برنامج التحقيقات الصحفية
at U.C. Berkeley,
في جامعة كاليفونيا بيركلي
and a research assistant and I
أنا ومساعد بحث
put together a database of all terrorism prosecutions
وضعنا قاعدة بيانات لجميع محاكمات الإرهاب
at the time during the first decade after 9/11.
خلال العقد الذي يلي أحداث 11 سبتمبر
And we used the court file to find out whether
واستخدمنا ملف المحكمة لمعرفة ما إذا كان
the defendants had any connections to international terrorist groups,
للمتهمين أية صلة بالجماعات الإرهاب الدولي
whether an informant was used,
سواء كانت تستخدم مخبرا
and whether the informant played the role of an agent provocateur
أو إذا كان المخبر يلعب دورا محرّضا
by providing the means and opportunity.
بتوفير كل الوسائل والفرص
And we submitted that to the FBI
وقدمنا ​​ذلك إلى "م ت ف"
and we asked them to respond to our database.
وطلبنا منهم الرد على قاعدة البيانات لدينا
If they believed there were any errors,
إذا كانوا يعتقدون أن هناك أية أخطاء
we asked them to tell us what they were and we'd go back and check
طلبنا منهم أن يخبرونا ما إذا كانت وسوف نعود ونتحقق
and they never challenged any of our findings.
ولم يطعنوا أبدا فيما توصلنا إليه
Later, I used that data in a magazine article
لاحقا، استعملت هذه البيانات في مقال بمجلة
and later in my book,
وبعدها في كتابي
and on appearances on places like CBS and NPR,
وظهرت على شبكة كولومبيا والإذاعة الوطنية
they were offered that opportunity again
قُدمت لهم هذه الفرصة مرة أخرى
to say, "Trevor Aaronson's findings are wrong."
للقول أن نتائج تريفور أرونسون خاطئة
And they've never come forward and said,
لم يفعلوا أو يقولوا هذا أبدا
"These are the problems with those findings."
"هذه هي المشاكل مع هذه النتائج "
So the data has since been used by groups like Human Rights Watch
هكذا بدأ استخدام البيانات من طرف جماعات مثل هيومن رايتس ووتش
on its recent report on these types of sting operations.
في تقريرها الأخير حول هذه الأنواع من العمليات الإستباقية
And so far, the FBI has never really responded
وحتى الآن، لم يقدم "م ت ف" أي رد
to these charges that it's really not catching terrorists
على هذه الاتهامات بعدم القبض على إرهابيين
so much as it's catching mentally ill people
قدر القبض على مرضى عقليين
that it can dress up as terrorists in these types of sting operations.
يمكن إظهارهم كإرهابيين في هذا النوع من الضربات
TR: So The Intercept is that new investigative journalism website,
ت. رايلي:"ذا انترسبت" هل هي ذلك الموقع الجديد لصحافة التحقيقات
that's cofounded by Glenn Greenwald.
التي أسست من طرف "غلن غرينوالد"
Tell us about your article and why there.
أخبرنا عن مقالك ولماذا هناك
TA: The Intercept seemed to be the most logical place for this
تريفور: يبدو أن "ذا انترسبت" المكان الأكثر منطقية لهذا
because my article is really leveraging the fact that
لأن مقالتي تستفيد فعلاً من حقيقة أن
a source had leaked to me transcripts of these
أن مصدرا سرّب لي وثائق
private FBI conversations that a federal judge had sealed
لمحادثات خاصة لـ"م ت ف" تفيد أن قاضيا فدراليا أغلقها
based on the government's claim that their release
بناء على اعتقاد الحكومة أن الإفراج عنهم
would irreparably damage the U.S. government's
سيُضِر بشكل لا يمكن إصلاحه باستراتيجية
law enforcement strategy.
إنفاذ القانون للحكومة الامريكية
So a place like The Intercept was set up to protect journalists
لهذا فمكان ك"ذا انترسبت" أنشئ لحماية الصحفيين
and publish their work
ونشر أعمالهم
when they're dealing with very sensitive matters like this.
عندما نتعامل مع مسائل حساسة جدا كهذه
So my story in The Intercept, which was just published today,
حتى قصتي في "ذا انترسبت" والتي نشرت اليوم فقط
tells the story of how Sami Osmakac was set up in this FBI sting
تروي قصة سامي أوسماكاش وكيف تم إعداده في ضربة "م ت ف" الاستباقية
and goes into much greater detail.
وذهبت إلى قدر كبير من تفاصيل
In this talk, I could only highlight the things that they said,
في هذه المحادثة، يمكنني فقط تسليط الضوء على الأمور التي قالوا
such as calling him a "retarded fool."
مثل وصفه بأنه "معتوه متخلف"
But it was much more elaborate,
لكنها كانت مدروسة بعناية أكبر
they went to great lengths to put money in Sami Osmakac's hands,
ذهبوا إلى أبعد من ذلك بوضع المال في يد سامي أوسماكاش
which he then used to purchase weapons from the undercover agent.
الذي استعمله فيما بعد لشراء السلاح من عميل سري
When he went to trial,
عندما ذهب إلى المحاكمة
the central piece of evidence was that he paid for these weapons,
الدليل الرئيسي هو أنه دفع لهذه الأسلحة
when in truth, these transcripts show how the FBI orchestrated
وفي الحقيقة, هذه النصوص تظهر كيف أن "م ت ف" تدبر
someone who was essentially mentally ill and broke
لشخص كان في الأساس مختلاًّ عقليا ومطرودا
to get money to then pay for weapons
المال لشراء السلاح
that they could then charge him in a conspiracy for.
ليستطيعوا بعدها اتهامه في المؤامرة
TR: One final question.
ت. رايلي: سؤال أخير
Less than 10 days ago,
أقل من عشرة أيام مضت
the FBI arrested some potential ISIS suspects in Brooklyn,
أوقف "م ت ف" بعض المشتبهين بالانتماء لداعش في بروكلين
saying that they might be headed to Syria,
قائلين أنه كان من الممكن توجههم إلى سوريا
and were those real, or examples of more of the same?
هل كان هؤلاء فعلا كذلك، أم مزيد من نفس النموذج
TA: Well so far, we only know what's come out in the court file,
تريفور: حسنا حتى الآن، نحن نعلم فقط ما يخرج في ملف المحكمة،
but they seem to suggest it's another example of the same.
ولكن يبدو أنها تشير إلى انها مثال آخر على ما قلنا
These types of sting operations have moved from flavor to flavor.
هذه الأنواع من العمليات انتقلت من نكهة إلى نكهة
So initially it was al Qaeda plots,
كان ذلك في البداية أنها مؤامرات تنظيم القاعدة
and now the Islamic State is the current flavor.
والآن الدولة الإسلامية هي النكهة الحالية
What's worth noting about that case is that the three men that were charged
ما الجدير بالذكر حول هذه الحالة غير أن الرجال الثلاثة الذين اتهموا
only began the plot to go to Syria
فقط في بداية مؤامرة للذهاب إلى سوريا
after the introduction of the FBI informant,
بعد تدخل مخبر لـ"م ت ف"
and in fact, the FBI informant had helped them with the travel documents
و في الحقيقة فقد ساعدهم المخبر في وثائق السفر
that they needed.
التي يحتاجونها
In kind of a comical turn in that particular case,
كنوع من العرض الكوميدي في هذه الحالة
one of the defendant's mother had found out
والدة أحد المتهمين تبين لها
that he was interested in going to Syria and had hid his passport.
أنه كان مهتما بالذهاب إلى سوريا وأخفى جواز سفره
that he ever could have gone anywhere.
إذن نعم، هناك أشخاص قد يهتمون بالانضمام إلى الدولة الإسلامية
In this particular case, given the evidence that's so far come out,
تشير إلى أن "م ت ف" مكّن هؤلاء الرجال
when they were never close to that in the first place.
ت رايلي: شكرا جزيلا, هذا مدهش تريفور: شكرا لكم